{
    "id": "53e7fbfad3864f7d99918df5e9672b19",
    "title": "Omission | Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "They went out despite of the rain.",
            "description": "‘Of’ should be removed from the sentence. The correct preposition is despite. ",
            "answers": [
                "out",
                "of",
                "the"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Merlin, who is my youngest sister, she lives in Qatar.",
            "description": "‘She’ should be removed from the sentence. A clause cannot have more than one subject.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "she",
                "youngest"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "No matter what that I do, nothing seems to work.",
            "description": "‘That’ should be removed from the sentence. ",
            "answers": [
                "no",
                "what",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He is at the work and won’t be home before evening.",
            "description": "‘The’ should be removed from the sentence. There is no article in the expression ‘at work’.",
            "answers": [
                "at",
                "the",
                "be"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It is getting dark. Let us go to home.",
            "description": "Home is used without to as an adverb referring to direction.",
            "answers": [
                "getting",
                "let",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I have received the parcel last week.",
            "description": "We cannot use the present perfect tense with past time expressions.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "the",
                "last"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "You had better to put the meat in the oven.",
            "description": "After had better we use the infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "had",
                "better",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You have to tell to me exactly how it happened.",
            "description": "We do not use a preposition between tell and its object. The sentence should read: You have to tell me exactly how it happened.",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "have",
                "how"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If something does not work, I usually give to it a kick.",
            "description": "There is no preposition between give and an indirect object.",
            "answers": [
                "does",
                "to",
                "usually"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t know that how we are going to get over the river.",
            "description": "‘That’ should be removed from the sentence. The sentence should read: I don’t know how we are going to get over the river.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "how",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Have you ever tried to get a toothpaste back into the tube?",
            "description": "The article ‘a’ should be removed.",
            "answers": [
                "ever",
                "a",
                "back"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We have got our roof blown off in the storm last week.",
            "description": "We cannot use the present perfect tense with past time expressions.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "off",
                "the"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}